Pisciolari, Antonela

Software Engineer Córdoba, Argentina +54 9 3517658617

e-mail: antopiscio@gmail.com

Summary

Software Engineer with 6 years of professional experience working as Quality Assurance engineer and automation tester for Web Applications and Web Services (WSDL and Restful APIs). Leader for the testing activities by performing validation tasks that involved designing automation test cases, define tests plans, coordinating and planning the executions, executing regression tests in order to assure the quality for every release. Reporting and tracking problems or improvements found in the product. Strong communication, fast adaptation to changes and learner, compromise, responsibility, commitment and leadership skills. Strongly committed to achieve results at work and true believer in agile development.

Relevant work experience

September 2016 - Today

Sr QA Analyst, GlobalLogic, Argentina (REMOTE)

- Define Test strategy, QA plan and validation plan
- Test cases design and test automation using test solution implemented in Groovy using Selenium
- Working as Scrum Master and in continuous communication with the clients for better stories definitions.
- Using Jira as a story and defect tracking tool, integrated with bamboo for Continuous Integration
- Working Remotely

January 2016 - August 2016

Sr QA Engineer, Intel Corporation, Argentina

- Define Test strategy, QA plan and validation plan
- Test cases design and test automation
- Create test suite using a Testing solution implemented in Python, to create component and functional tests, among others.
- Bug tracking using Rally
- Manage outsource QA team, organizing and tracking tasks and reporting results

February, 2015 - January 2016

Software QA Analyst II, Experian SA, Santiago, Chile

- Create a test solution for the automation of internal products.
- Define a new test Strategy.
- Execution of test on z/OS systems though TSO/ISPF interface and IBM Rational Developer Tools.

- Design, develop, plan and execute test case scenarios, as well as regression testing and problem reporting.
- Trace of user stories.
- Maintain and revise Audit Plan and Schedule in line with project epics/stories.
- Provide support and assistance to the Project on quality, certification and verification/validation issues.
- Experience working in a KANBAN environment following agile practices

January 17, 2011 - October 10, 2014

C# QA Tester, Intel Corporation, Córdoba, Argentina

- Design, develop, plan and execute test case scenarios, as well as regression testing and problem reporting. Design and development of Performance test. Trace of user stories. Maintain and revise Audit Plan and Schedule in line with project epics/stories. Provide support and assistance to the Project on quality, certification and verification/ validation issues. All this using C#, MySql, Selenium, SOAPUI, Quality Center, Jira, JMeter, among others
- Experience working in a scrum environment following agile practices.

January 12, 2014 - December, 2014

Web automation Consultant, CIDS - Centro de Investigación y Desarrollo de Sistemas - UTN, Córdoba, Argentina

Design the architecture of the test solution using Selenium webdriver in Java. Assist in the coding
and maintenance of automated testing execution frameworks. Write automated test scripts using
functional automation tools using agreed standards and tools. Perform maintenance on own and
others automated test scripts. Work closely with other team members to gather automated testing
requirements. Inform other teams of faults found when required. Represent TTP at meetings with
client teams to discuss the automated testing needs of the project

October 1, 2010

Web Developer, Coined, Córdoba, Argentina

- Part of a cross geo team.
- Responsible for the update and maintenance of the web pages of the company. Using Kanban method, developing the new features, doing bug fixing using ASP, HTML, C# and SQL server.

Languages, Technologies and Skills

- C#.NET, Java, Python, Groovy, HTML, XML, SQL Server, MySql, Maven, Ant, JanRain, SOAP, Rest.
- Eclipse, NetBeans, Visual Studio, PostMan, SOAPUI, Quality Center, Jira, Enterprise Tester, SCM Bamboo, Heidi, SVN, Mercurial, Cassandra, Git, Gerrit, Rally, Team City
- Robot Framework, Selenium, Mainframe, MVC, UML, Spring, JSON, JUnit, RESTFul, JMeter.

Education

Universidad Tecnológica Nacional

Diplomacy in Software Engineering and Quality - December 2012

Bachelor's Degree in System Engineer - December 2012

Courses

ISTQB "Certified Tester Advanced Level Test Manager" course - July 2015

Scrum: Framework for Agile Project Management – December 2013

Datastax - Cassandra - October 2013

Python Programming Language (Level I) - May 2013

DEFENSIC Codenomicon - Jan 2013

Additional Experience

Part of a research investigation team at Universidad Tecnológica Nacional – "Defining a protocol of procedures regarding statistical metrics associated with process, development and continuous improvement of software".